A Guide to the Papers of Willa Cather, 1899-1949
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series IV: Miscellaneous Documents, Printed Matter
  - Carbon typescript of review from New York Sun of My Antonia[1918] October 6, AD, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 3:72)
    With autograph corrections. [no accession number]
  - Paper Dolls or People, review of My Antonia1919 April 12, printed, 1 item. (Box-folder 3:73)
    Reprinted from The Chicago Daily News. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather: Civilized and Very American 1940 December 15, newspaper clipping, 1 item. (Box-folder 3:74)
    From New York Herald Tribune Books. #6494-b
  - The Literary Spotlight by Fanny Butcher 1949 September 25, newspaper clipping, 2 items. (Box-folder 3:75)
    Review of Willa Cather on Writing. #6494-b
  - Newspaper clippings regarding Willa Cather n.d., Printed, 2 items. (Box-folder 3:76)
    #6494-c
  - Newspaper clippings: Willa Cather obituaries 1947 April, Printed, 2 items. (Box-folder 3:77)
  - Miscellaneous news clippings/articles n.d. (Box-folder 3:78)
    The Point of View Was Masculine, review of Willa: The Life of Willa Cather by Phyllis C. Robinson. Willa Cather: A Lady Lost and Found, review of Willa Cather: Early Novels and Stories and Willa Cather: The Emerging Voice by Sharon O'Brien. Stamp Honors Famed Novelist Willa Cather. Willa Cather: Her Artistry Endures in a Different Age. An Epic Vision of Nebraska, review of Willa: The Life of Willa Cather by Phyllis C. Robinson. Bakst. Painfully Becoming Herself, review of Willa Cather: The Emerging Voice. Musical Menuhins to Pay Homage to Willa. #6494-r
- Series V: Photographs, Etchings, Busts
  - Photograph of Elsie Cather as a child with Marjorie Anderson (Cather family servant) in Red Cloud, Nebraska n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:79)
    Photograph by Wegmann. #6494-c
  - Autographed photograph of Willa Cather, seated, inscribed to the Rev. Delos W. O'Brian n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:80)
    8 x 10 black and white photograph. #6494-e
  - Autographed printed photograph of Willa Cather, inscribed "Cordially Yours, Willa Cather" n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:81)
    #6494-z
  - Autographed photograph of Willa Cather, inscribed "Cordially Yours, Willa Cather" n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:82)
    Matted photograph. #6494-b
  - Autographed photograph of Willa Cather, signed twice: top right corner and bottom n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:83)
  - Autographed photograph of Willa Cather, inscribed "For Philip de Navarro" n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:84)
    Inscribed line from Cather's poem, A Likeness. With 5x7 black and white reproduction and 9x12 negative print copy. #6494
  - Autographed photograph of Willa Cather and [Duncan Vinsonhaler?] 1923 October, 1 item. (Box-folder 3:85)
    Inscribed "For Duncan M. Vinsonhaler from his friend Willa Cather." Mounted 8 x 10 black and white photograph. #6494-r
  - Photograph of Willa Cather, seated, in velvet dress n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:86)
    Formerly laid in J. Huneker's book, Painted Veils. #6494-p
  - Photograph of Willa Cather n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:87)
    Photograph by Nicholas Muray, New York. #6494-b
  - Photograph of [Willa Cather?] n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:87a)
  - Newspaper clipping of photograph of Willa Cather n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:88)
  - Photograph of a black crayon portrait of Willa Cather n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:89)
    Crayon portrait by Nicolai Fehin. Copyright belongs to Dr. Paul M. Beigelman, 46 rue de l'Universite, 75007 Paris, France. Original in the possession of Los Angeles County Museum of Art. #10462-c
  - Postcard of Willa Cather n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:90)
    #7267-a
  - Magazine clipping: photograph of Willa Cather n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:91)
    Glued onto 5 x 7 index card. Includes photocopy of 20 slides from Willa Cather Pioneer Memorial, Red Cloud, Nebraska. Barrett Prints Reference Collection.
  - Photograph of etching of Willa Cater by Richard Hood n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:92)
    Original framed etching in Oversize Box O-1. #6494-k
  - Photograph of Willa Cather's childhood home, Willow Shade, Virginia n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:93)
    See Willa Cather letter dated May 16, 1941. #6494-c
  - Photograph of Willa Cather's home in Red Cloud, Nebraska n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:94)
  - Willa Cather's home in Red Cloud, Nebraska n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 3:95)
    Original charcoal drawing, mounted on board, with accompanying photograph of the drawing
    #7267
  - Magazine clipping: photograph of Willa Cather n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:96)
  - Magazine clipping: photograph of Willa Cather by Steichen n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:97)
    Includes brief description of Cather's work below photograph. #6494-b
  - Magazine clipping: photograph of Willa Cather [ca. 1927 July], 1 item. (Box-folder 3:98)
    Removed from Vanity Fair Magazine. #6494
  - Photographs of Willa Cather bust by Paul Swan n.d., 6 items. (Box-folder 3:99)
    #10560
  - Photograph of actor George Arliss n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:100)
    Inscribed and signed to Willa Cather by George Arliss. #6494-m
  - Plaster cast bust of Willa Cather by Paul Swan n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:101)
    Made from the original bust displayed at the State Capitol in Lincoln, Nebraska, 26" high. Located in Barrett Room. #10560
- Series VI: Uncollected Published Works
  Photocopies of Willa Cather's "uncollected" published works, assembled in two volumes by James B. Meriwether, Professor of English at the University of South Carolina, "to assist me in teaching a graduate seminar."
  - Eric Hermannson's Soul April 1890, Printed, 13 pp. (Box-folder 4:1)
    from The Cosmopolitan. Photocopy. #6494-n
  - Volume I: Fiction [1896-1933], 1 volume. (Box-folder 4:2)
    p.1: On the Divide, from The Overland Monthly, January 1896, pp. 65-75. p.13: El Dorado: A Kansas Recessional, from New England Magazine, June 1901, pp. 357-369. p. 27: The Namesake, from McClure's, March 1907, pp. 492-497. p. 35: The Profile, from McClure's, June 1907, pp. 135-141. p. 43: The Willing Muse, from Century magazine, August 1907, pp. 550-557. p. 51: Eleanor's House, from McClure's, October 1907, pp. 623-630. p. 59: On the Gulls' Road, from McClure's, December 1908, pp. 145-152. p. 67: The Joy of Nelly Deane, from Century magazine, October 1911, pp. 859-866. p. 77: Behind the Singer Tower, from Collier's magazine, May 1912, pp. 16-20. p. 83: The Bohemian Girl, from McClure's, August 1912, pp. 420-443. p. 107: Consequences, from McClure's, November 1915. p. 115: The Bookkeeper's Wife, from Century magazine, May 1916, pp. 51-59. p. 125: Ardessa, from Century magazine, May 1918, pp. 105-116. p. 137: Uncle Valentine, from Women's Home Companion, February 1925. p. 151: The Story of Pavel and Peter (from My Antonia), from The Golden Book, May 1933, pp. 459-460. p. 153: Jack-a-Boy, from T he Saturday Evening Post, March 1901. p. 157: The Professor's Commencement, from New England Magazine, June 1902, pp. 481-488. p. 165: The Treasure of Far Island, from New England Magazine, October 1902, pp. 234-249. #6494-n
  - The House on Charles Street 1922 November 4, 1 item, 2 pp. (Box-folder 4:3)
    from The Literary Review. Photocopy. #6494-n
  - Volume II: Non-Fiction [1891-1923], 1 volume. (Box-folder 4:4)
    p. 1: Concerning Thomas Carlyle: Some of his personal characteristics, from The Nebraska State Journal, March 1, 1891, p. 14. p. 3: The Personal Side of William Jennings Bryan, from The Prairie Schooner, date not noted [post July 1900], pp. 331-336, reprinted from the Library (Pittsburg, PA), July 14, 1900, where it appeared under the pen name Henry Nicklemann. p. 9: When I Knew Stephen Crane, from The Prairie Schooner, date not noted [post July 1900], pp. 231-236, reprinted from the Library (Pittsburg, PA), June 23, 1900, where it appeared under the pen name Henry Nicklemann; it also appeared in the Lincoln Courier, July 14, 1900. p. 15: The Man Who Wrote 'Narcissus,' from The Ladies Home Journal, November 1900. p. 19: Introduction to 'The Secrets of the Schluesselburg' by David Soskice, from McClure's, December 1909, pp. 144-145. p. 21: Plays of Real Life, from McClure's, March 1913, pp. 63-72. p. 31: Training for the Ballet, from McClure's, October 1913, pp. 85-95. p. 43: Three American Singers: Louise Homer, G. Farrar, Olive Frenstad, from McClure's, December 1913, pp. 33-48. #6494-n